Marietta, GA, United States eebesos@hotmail.com

Robert Sosebee

A humble team manager, creative problem solver, and a polyglot software developer seeking a challenge to improve lives through technology. I get most enjoyment out of delivering successful products for both internal and external customers. I have shipped products written in C#, Typescript, Javascript, Visual Basic, and even QBasic.

15 years as a software developer in the insurance industry. Full stack developer specializing in the Microsoft technology stack, cloud computing, and desktop development.

Technical Skills

Likes: C#, Git, Typescript, Javascript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, agile methodologies, Visual Basic

Experience

Development Team Manager - Assurance Systems, Inc.

**C#*, .net, wpf, silverlight, amazonec2, amazons3, typescript, javascript, html5, css, phantomjs, casperjs, mongodb, sql, visual basic, xml

Nov 2014 - Current

Carrent**

Nov 2014 - Current**

Carrent**

Project Scoping and Planning - figuring out what needs to happen to get a project done and getting all the parts of the project into a workable state for development

Process Control - getting tasks assigned out and completed in an efficient manner. From requirements through to QA and release

Release Management and Deployments - coordinated released to QA and production and communicating these with all parties involved.

Manage remote development and QA teams - manage relationships with development team, QA, and tech support teams. Facilitate communication.

Technology - Monitoring and implementing use of productivity tools

Administration - keeping track of work schedules, vacation time and job performance for the development team.

Team Staffing - Create job postings interview, and hire/train new developers/QA staff.

Software Engineer - Assurance Systems, Inc. Feb 2001 - Nov 2014 c#, .net, wpf, silverlight, amazonec2, amazons3, typescript, javascript, phantomjs, casperjs, mongodb, sql, visual basic, btrieve, qbasic, xml, coypu

Lead developer with rating modules, bridge APIs, credit web services, and screen scraping projects. Full stack web developer with Silverlight front end, C# and Visual Basic back end, and MongoDB database.

Served as an expert with internal and external stakeholders on over 50 projects in many areas of our development stack.

Served as an integral part in converting QBasic to Visual Basic with not knowing either language well at the time.

Education

B.S. Computer Science - University of North Georgia

1996-2000

Received academic and tennis scholarships

Played singles and doubles on NAIA collegiate tennis team in,1996, 1997, and 1998.

Member of Kappy Sigma National Fraternity

VFR Pilot (incomplete)- Bob Hughes Flight Academy at Peachtree Dekalb 1996

Volunteer/ Community

Tournament Director - Hall County Tennis

Sept 2010

Directed a very successful 7 day long tennis tournament consisting of over 100 matches at 3 facilities. It was the biggest non USTA tournament held in Northeast Georgia

Worked with sponsors to generate over \$100 worth of swag and expensive sweat wicking shirt for each entrant, and have 3 days of meals catered at the tournament. Entry fee was only \$25.

Designed popular tournament logo.

Persuaded several friends to volunteer their big screen TVs to have a Wii tennis tournament for spectators and players alike.

Driver - Transportation Committee - Atlanta BB&T Open Tennis Championship

July 2013

This hard court tournament is the first of the US Open Series and is an ESPN televised event.

Responsible for driving VIPs and professional tennis players to and from hotel, airport, restaurants, and practice courts.

Trail Builder - Southern Off Road Biking Association (SORBA)

Sept 2004 - Oct 2006

Volunteered efforts in maintaining trails in North Georgia. Specifically with Carter's Lake, Chicope, and Pinhotti Trail systems.

Business Ambassador and Sponsorship Lead - American Cancer Society

Apr 2014 -

Current

Serve as the main point of contact and help teams meet and exceed their fundraising goals by utilizing tools and resources. Engage in the mission of ACS.

As sponsorship lead: Retain and recruit volunteers to help with sponsor fundraising, recognition, and stewardship. Leverage kickoffs,

Tools

First Computer - Apple Macintosh

Favorite Editor - Visual Studio 2015 w/ Resharper and Sublime 3

Source Control - Git